# Santiago Aguirre

 $\P \ \, \text{Montevideo, Uruguay} \ \, \blacksquare \ \, \text{santiago.aguirre@hey.com} \ \, \square \ \, \text{+59899670932} \ \, \blacksquare \ \, \text{https://www.linkedin.com/in/santiago-aguirre-717248161/}$ 

https://santiagoaguirre.info

### **SUMMARY**

Software Engineer with 5+ years of experience, with strong technical foundation in a variety of tools and frameworks. My hard skills include proficiency in React, Next.js, NodeJS, and .NET Core. I have worked on a range of projects, from web applications to back-end systems, and I am comfortable with both front-end and back-end development.

In addition to my technical skills, I possess excellent communication skills, which allow me to collaborate effectively with stakeholders and team members. I am committed to delivering high-quality work and have a keen attention to detail that ensures my code is efficient and error-free.

My ability to communicate clearly and deliver work that meets client needs makes me a valuable asset for any project. Whether working independently or as part of a team, I am dedicated to delivering exceptional results that exceed client expectations.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### Senior Frontend Web3 Engineer

# Swoops

### August 2022 - Present, Berkeley, CA

- Develop and maintain the frontend architecture of a Web3 strategy basketball game that utilizes real ownership and NFTs, creating a seamless user experience for players.
- · Prioritize and implement user-centric features closely with product owners and designers that increase engagement and retention.
- · Lead the integration of various Web3 technologies, including MetaMask and Web3.js, to enable seamless blockchain transactions and NFT ownership verification.
- Design and implement a responsive and intuitive user interface, leveraging React, NextJS, and Tailwindcss, to enhance the overall user experience and drive user engagement.
- Conduct extensive testing and optimization to ensure the game's performance and scalability, leveraging tools like Google Lighthouse, Jest, and Cypress.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams, including backend developers and blockchain engineers, to ensure seamless integration of frontend and backend functionality.
- · Actively monitor and analyze user feedback, usage patterns and metrics with the help of Sentry and Hotjar, to inform ongoing product development and iterate on the frontend experience.

#### Senior Fullstack Engineer

#### Light-it

#### March 2022 - July 2022, Aventura, FL

- · Managed a 5 person team, from the Tech Lead position. Instrumental in core architectural and design decisions from the start of the project.
- · Developed from scratch using ReactJS, NextJS, Ethers.js (w/ Typescript) and Solidity.
- Implemented smart contracts using the HardHat framework.
- Integrated ERC-721 standard contracts for the tracking of Drugs in the production chain.
- Designed for Ethereum based networks, while also thoroughly investigating Permissioned hyperledgers for the purpose of this project.
- · Integrated with websockets, Solidity Events and stored in-chain images (as opposed to storing images in IPFS).

# **Fullstack Engineer**

#### **Switch Software Solutions**

### February 2018 - March 2022, Montevideo, Uruguay

- · Developed and implemented complex platforms for multibillion-dollar companies, like Odyssey Reinsurance.
- Proficient in programming languages and frameworks including ReactJS, NodeJS, Angular 2+, .NET Core, and React Native.
- $\cdot \ \text{Designed and built data processing pipelines and displayed data in various types of charts using ChartJS.}$
- · Implemented Pipes & Filters pattern in order to reduce time complexity of processing pipeline by 40%.
- Ensured conformance to security regulations pertaining to user and governmental information.
- · Integrated with location APIs and identity providers using the Federated identity architectural pattern.
- · Managed real-time IoT input data and used message queues for processing and reporting information.
- Optimized platform performance and availability by adding caches, message queues, and a load balancer for intra-system communication which resulted in a 35% reduction in response time.

- · Co-authored design system with UX/UI designer for supermarket chain group applications.
- · Led automated testing efforts, involving unit, end-to-end, and integration tests.

# **PROJECTS**

### **Portfolio**

Personal · February 2023 - March 2023

- Developed and deployed a portfolio website to showcase professional achievements with fully customizable design and updated content, resulting in a 356% increase in website traffic in the first two months.
- · Utilized Git version control to manage code, created branches and merged pull requests upon testing and approval.
- · Leveraged sophisticated animation tools to customize website and create an interactive user experience.
- · Streamlined website to ensure efficiency and fast loading time, decreasing page response time by 23%.
- · Incorporated responsive design to optimize UX on different device sizes.

### **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor of Science in Computer Science**

ORT University, Montevideo · Montevideo, Uruguay. · 2023 · 3.4

### **SKILLS**

Front End: React.js, Next.js, HTML, CSS, Tailwindcss.

Back End: Node.js, Nest.js, .NET Core, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB.